Carney Burns III

(914) 525-4589 | crb565@gmail.com | New York, NY linkedin.com/in/CARNEY-BURNS-III | github.com/Cod3ingKing

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Attentive problem-solving professional with web development and programming skills necessary to become a web developer. Results driven team leader experienced in financial operations, event organization, social media management and website design efforts. Interested in joining ----- in the ---- in order to further develop JavaScript, Node.js and app building (Backend/Frontend abilities) skills.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

W3schools JavaScript Certificate | December 2023

- Git/ GitHub
- JavaScript
- SCRUM

- HTML
- Node.Js
- CSS

- Bootstrap Bash Scripts
- Website Building
- Microsoft Office Suite

EXPERIENCE

Generation USA Junior Web Development Program | Washington D.C | July 2022 - December 2022

Training Participant

 Participated in a 21-week Junior Web Developer program learning how web development works, from the fundamentals of JavaScript, computer programming, developer tools, Git version control, and problem solving needed to be successful as a web developer.

Today's Students Tomorrow's Teachers | White Plains, NY | May 2020 - Present

Operations Manager

- Raised over \$200,000 in donations through effective fundraising strategies and management of a major donor database, while authoring grants and facilitating multiple donor campaigns
- Developed a participant database with over 2,000 educational records utilizing efficient management of information and communication
- Collaborated with the accountant to manage financial operations including filing claims, audits and accurate financial record maintenance
- Spearheaded social media management and website design efforts resulting in a 40% increase in brand awareness and new registrants
- Organized and executed 10+ successful virtual and live special events averaging 200 guests

New Rochelle Racket Club | New Rochelle, NY | October 2019 – February 2021

Program Manager

- Managed financial operations and program coordination, including scheduling for a team of 10-15
- Improved staff performance through mentoring resulting in more effective conflict resolutions and increased customer satisfaction
- Quick problem solving during major tournaments when managing court assignments

Mioym Equities | New Rochelle, NY | March 2019 – October 2019

Real Estate Acquisition Specialist

- Reviewed and analyzed real estate contracts which resulted in 38% increase in closings
- Evaluated properties values to accurately make offers
- Negotiated contracts with realtors for the successful purchase of multiple properties, applying strong communication and interpersonal skills.

EDUCATION

Binghamton University | Vestal, NY | May 2017

• Bachelor of Arts in Urban Planning, emphasis in Retailing and Economics